Hello,

I am..

My name is **Alan Rey Rios**. It's an interesting name when considering its translations. Translations tend to stir my curiosity in our people especially when it involves someone's name. It shows how we can come from different lands and different languages and still be able to bridge that gap that can be created from a language barrier with simple connections.

In true go with the flow style my character takes after my last name Rios which is Spanish for rivers. Rivers are a force of nature that is able to shape the environment around it through **determined perserverence** in its forward motion. They are also tranquil waters that spread life. Rivers were also the first major transportation methods for different industries as humanity grew.

Although Alan is a simple name it is pretty neat. My ego and self confidence flourished under its original translation of smart and handsome. I prefer the Finnish translation to industry due to my obsession with disrupting the world around me as a **serial wantrepreneur** in the sense that I want to be an entrepreneur in many different industries. This does not come from a need to make money but from a need to solve different problems and lead the market in solving them correctly.

Leading is something that I am very familiar with due to my middle name. To me leading is not a strive to control or have power over someone but instead to bear the **responsibilities** of those around you. My middle name is Spanish for king and I understand that my kingdom depends on the quality of leadership that I provide to it.

I think...

The world around us is in a constant state of evolving. This comes from a need to get better. While not all people are individually striving towards this goal there are those many that believe that anything, no matter how big or small, can be slightly **improved to better** those involved. This is something that I live by every day.

Through competitive swimming I have had the luxury of understanding the amount of effort that goes into top level competition. To be better than the competition comes in different tiers. It starts by refining technique and training strength. As our body's abilities start to plateau the winning force depends on mistakes made. As discipline irons out everything out then it starts to depend on belief. To truly understand what it takes to be the best it takes everything: **body**, **mind**, **and spirit**.

There wasn't always a coach and a team to push me towards new goals and ambitions though. I owe a lot of myself to **growth by trial and error**. As a natural born scientist I understand the importance of educated guesses with accompanying experiments to come to a proper conclusion. This process of learning is not limited to typical science fields. This can apply to all areas. This life style has allowed me to excel in everything that I have sought after including skills with people.

As a self proclaimed introvert I would not have thought myself one to excel in positions that involve not only communicating with people but guiding them to make the best decisions. This ability does not come from being a people person but instead comes from a need to dissect the world around me and **build upon** it. From intense observations and thorough experimenting coupled with an extraordinary drive to be a better person than before I will excel at all.

I will..

There is a confidence in one's own person and one's own abilities that is able to determine the successes in their lives. My own understanding of my aptitude and adaptability is what turns my confidence into a solid knowing of not only my success but the success of those around me. I intend to use my competence to **inspire all around me** to be the best versions of themselves the same way I strive to be the best me.

I will surpass what is expected of my role at this company. I will showcase my strengths and abilities beyond convention. I will **transcend barriers** and positively impact this company as a whole. I will be a fantastic asset to this company.

Alan R Rios

1956 Winrock Blvd #0339 Houston, TX 77057

(713) 732-9085

i@alanrrios.com

linkedin.com/in/ /alanrrios

> github.com/ /alanrrios

alanrrios.com

SUMMARY

My goal for the immediate future is to utilize my strengths and talents to succeed in new endeavors. By applying my experience, abilities, and good work ethic, I can greatly benefit your organization. Since I enjoy being with people and have a positive outlook, I have been successful in the past working with the public and look forward to using my people skills in the future.

My goals for the distant future include using all of the skills and experiences I've gathered and apply them as best as possible to all of my entrepreneurial projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Specialist, Apple

Houston, TX — August 2016 - PRESENT

As a Technical Specialist at Apple I assist customers with any issues involving their iOS devices. This involves resolving relations with their devices through a connection made during our swift session. By connecting with the customer in front of me I am better able to assess any other services Apple can provide while maintaining the best world class service.

Geek Squad - Technology Education Agent, Best Buy

Houston, TX — July 2015 - August 2016

As a Technology Education Agent at Best Buy I would manage clinics and classroom-based training sessions to help our clients understand, control, and experience their technology to its fullest extent. I was required to have a thorough and up to date knowledge on all services, technologies, and store business strategies. On top of educating clients, I would also work closely with other Best Buy employees to ensure all the clients' technology needs were met and help them meet their business category goals.

Accomplishments

- Top 5 sales agent in the region.
- Multiple public positive customer reviews on Google.

Junior Server Admin, HostGator.com LLC

Houston, TX — July 2013 - July 2014

As a Junior Server Admin at HostGator I was in the front line of customer support for HostGator. I managed calls and chats with customers from with questions from all areas of business. This included quickly diagnosing and resolving and server issues as well as translating technical products into easy to understand services for purchasing.

I was required to have a technical knowledge of Server Hosting, Linux, ASP.NET, cPanel, WHM, WHMCS, Wordpress, DNS, Email routing, etc. I applied this knowledge to my sales talent to give customers the best website experience through many services.

Accomplishments

- Consistently top 05 out of hundreds on call ratings.
- Consistently top 10 out of hundreds on chat ratings.

EDUCATION

University of Houston - DowntownComputer Science — 2014 - 2017

Extra-Curricular Activities

True North Start Ups

Texas A&M - Corpus Christi Science and Engineering — 2012 - 2013

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Computer Science Club
- Cyber Defense Team
- Swim Club

REFERENCES Available upon request.